We're going to review the brain, and this time we're going to integrate it with the heart and the circulatory system.
脳をもう一度見て、今回は心臓と循環器系と統合します。
The mesenteric axis is the axis of rotation for the development system of my peritoneal framework.
腸間膜軸は、私の腹膜フレームワークの発達システムのための回転軸です。
It makes a downward movement, it starts again there, I change, I try to tilt and
それは下降運動をします。そこから再開し、私は変え、傾けようとします。
it happens like that.
そして、それはこのように起こります。
So finally, it makes a movement like this, like this.
結局、それはこのように、このような動きをします。
The brain does that.
脳はこれをします。
at the same time as I have that
これを持っていると同時に
at the same time I will have that
同時に私はこれを持つでしょう
at the same time at the level of my kidneys
同時に私の腎臓のレベルで
I will have that
私はこれを持つでしょう
at the level of my liver I will have that
私の肝臓のレベルで私はこれを持つでしょう
today we will review this motility
今日はこの運動性を見直します
of brain development
脳の発達の
and we will integrate it with what we have seen
そして、私たちがこれまで見てきたものと統合します
on the cardiac plane
心臓のレベルで
And we're going to see how the heart supports brain development.
そして、心臓が脳の発達をどのようにサポートするかを見ていきます。
Since, don't forget, the heart can be placed in the vitelline vesicle.
忘れないでください、心臓は卵黄嚢に入れることができます。
I take a landmark, which is my angle of Louis,
私のルイ角という目印を取ります。
because I know I'm in my second intercostal space.
なぜなら、私は第2肋間にあることを知っているからです。
I use my middle finger to go to the angle of Louis,
ルイ角に中指を置き、
I place my hand and put it in the axis of the heart, like this.
手を置いて、このように心臓の軸に合わせます。
Facially, this heart is more in pronation, so in diastole.
顔面では、この心臓はより回内しており、つまり拡張期にあります。
So that means it's looking for...
つまり、それは探しているということです...
You see? It's looking for something.
わかりますか？何かを探しています。
in the commitment of his life, he is more a little withdrawn than
彼の人生への関与において、彼は行動よりも少し引っ込み思案です。
in his action.
彼の行動において。
I place myself here at the hepatic level.
私はここに肝臓のレベルに身を置きます。
You put very little...
あなたはほとんど何も入れません...
You know, like there's an ant you can't crush.
ほら、潰せないアリがいるかのように。
Now, we wait.
今、待ちます。
I look at the liver because if it's a bit more horizontal,
肝臓が少し水平気味であれば、
that means the liver might be a bit swollen.
それは肝臓が少し腫れている可能性があることを意味します。
Does it change or not when we do a hepatic support?
肝臓に圧力をかけると、それは変わりますか、それとも変わりませんか？
It tends to go this way.
彼はこの方向に進む傾向があります。
Now, let's see here.
今、ここを見てみましょう。
Here, at the kidney level, I take a kidney, it goes more into pronation.
ここ、腎臓のレベルで、私は腎臓を取ります。それはより回内します。
So, it goes more into its lesion, well, in quotation marks.
つまり、彼は彼の病変に、まあ、いわば、より深く入っていくのです。
So, what does that mean?
つまり、どういうことでしょうか？
That it's more the kidney that destabilizes it here.
ここで彼を不安定にしているのは、むしろ腎臓だということです。
While the liver helps it.
一方、肝臓は彼を助けています。
So, the kidney, we know it's all that is related, on an emotional level, to fear.
腎臓は、感情的には恐怖と関係があることが分かっています。
This is someone who will look for a point of support, but his point here is a story that is blocked there.
彼は支えとなる点を探しますが、彼のここにある点は、そこに閉じ込められた物語です。
So, for this gentleman, I work on his kidneys to support his heart.
ですから、この男性の場合、私は彼の心臓を支えるために彼の腎臓を治療します。
The lungs, I remind you,
肺について思い出してください、
that its embryonic movement, if I repeat, is a movement that does this
その胚性運動は、繰り返しますが、このような動きをします。
while the heart does this with that movement after
一方、心臓は、この動きの後、このように動きます。
what do we do
私たちは何をしますか？
I did an induction towards its pronation, well towards diastole
私は彼の回内、つまり拡張期への誘導を行いました。
I support his kidneys, look what's going to happen, do you feel the difference?
彼の腎臓を支えます。何が起こるか見てください。違いを感じますか？
he wants to reorganize himself
彼は自分で再編成したいと思っています。
Because after, I will show you the motility of liver development, but with the vascular system.
その後、肝臓の発達の運動性、血管系との関係をお見せします。
We will also do the motility of kidney development, and see how we can support it.
腎臓の発達の運動性も行い、どのようにサポートできるかを見ます。
It must be remembered that the heart, in its form, is the result of the echo of its periphery.
心臓はその形において、その周辺のエコーの結果であるということを覚えておく必要があります。
That's why all the pulsology is super interesting.
だからこそ、脈診は非常に興味深いのです。
We can feel if it's a pulse that is more arterial type
純粋な動脈性の脈なのか、
pure, or a venous type pulse with stasis.
それともうっ滞を伴う静脈性の脈なのかを感じることができます。
For example here, it's a pulse...
例えば、ここでは、脈は...
For me, there are stases happening, and probably in the hepatic area.
私にとっては、うっ滞が起こっており、おそらく肝臓の領域で起こっていると思われます。
So, an arterial pulse, when you take it, it's a pulse that is...
動脈性の脈は、あなたがそれを取るとき、それは...
Whereas a venous pulse is a pulse that is more...
一方、静脈性の脈は、より...
Yet, it's on an artery that I feel that.
しかし、私は動脈でそれを感じています。
So, am I more in systole or in diastole, finally
では、私は最終的に収縮期と拡張期のどちらにいるのでしょうか？
?
？